<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ortelius User Guide and API Reference – Packaging Applications</title>
    <link>/guides/userguide/packaging-applications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Packaging Applications on Ortelius User Guide and API Reference</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="/guides/userguide/packaging-applications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Guides: Intro to Applications</title>
      <link>/guides/userguide/packaging-applications/buildingapplications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/guides/userguide/packaging-applications/buildingapplications/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;application-base-versions-and-versions&#34;&gt;Application Base Versions and Versions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Applications&lt;/em&gt; are main &lt;a href=&#34;/guides/userguide/concepts/basic-concepts/#application-object&#34;&gt;Objects&lt;/a&gt; in Ortelius. They are a collection of &lt;em&gt;Components&lt;/em&gt; that can be deployed as a single software solution. You define an &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; by associating the &lt;em&gt;Components&lt;/em&gt; it will consume. The first time you define an &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt;, it is referred to as the &lt;em&gt;Application Base Version.&lt;/em&gt; When you change the &lt;em&gt;Application Base Version&lt;/em&gt;, you create a new &lt;em&gt;Application Version&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Applications&lt;/em&gt; are assigned and deployed to &lt;em&gt;Environments&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Applications&lt;/em&gt; are associated to a &lt;em&gt;Domain&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application Base Version&lt;/strong&gt; : Defines the software product in terms of &lt;em&gt;Components&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Attributes,&lt;/em&gt; and assigned &lt;em&gt;Environments&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application Version&lt;/strong&gt; : This child of the &lt;em&gt;Application Base Version&lt;/em&gt; represents changes and can be deployed just as an &lt;em&gt;Application Base Version&lt;/em&gt; is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; and all objects within it will be deployed to one or more &lt;em&gt;Endpoints&lt;/em&gt;. (Each one represents a container, physical or virtual server in the enterprise in an &lt;em&gt;Environment&lt;/em&gt;. A backend versioning engine tracks all &lt;em&gt;Application Version&lt;/em&gt; configurations. For this reason, each new version will be given a new version number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, your Application Base Version may be called MyApp;1, subsequent versions would be automatically named MyApp;2, MyApp;3, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;applications-and-their-components&#34;&gt;Applications and their Components&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Applications&lt;/em&gt; are defined by the &lt;em&gt;Components&lt;/em&gt; they consume. As with &lt;em&gt;Applications&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Components&lt;/em&gt; have versions. If a new &lt;em&gt;Component&lt;/em&gt; is made available, Ortelius can be called by a continuous delivery tool to automatically create a new &lt;em&gt;Application Version&lt;/em&gt; each time a new build is detected.  For more information on this topic, see the &lt;a href=&#34;/guides/userguide/integrations/ci-cd_integrations/&#34;&gt;CD Engine Chapter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a new &lt;em&gt;Application Version&lt;/em&gt; is created from either an &lt;em&gt;Application Base Version&lt;/em&gt; or another &lt;em&gt;Application Version&lt;/em&gt;, it inherits all previous &lt;em&gt;Components&lt;/em&gt; and Attributes from its predecessor. You can create a new &lt;em&gt;Application Version&lt;/em&gt; from any previous version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;applications-and-tasks&#34;&gt;Applications and Tasks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tasks&lt;/em&gt; allow you to act upon &lt;em&gt;Applications&lt;/em&gt;. They are defined at the &lt;em&gt;Domain&lt;/em&gt; level and are available to all of the &lt;em&gt;Applications&lt;/em&gt; within the Domain as default &lt;em&gt;Tasks&lt;/em&gt;.  &lt;em&gt;Tasks&lt;/em&gt; can also be called via your continuous delivery pipeline.  Common &lt;em&gt;Tasks&lt;/em&gt; integrated into continuous delivery are &lt;em&gt;Move Version&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Approve&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Deploy&lt;/em&gt;. All &lt;em&gt;Tasks&lt;/em&gt; are managed at the &lt;em&gt;Domain&lt;/em&gt; level. For more information on Tasks and &lt;em&gt;Domains&lt;/em&gt; see &lt;a href=&#34;/guides/userguide/first-steps/2-defining-domains/#deployment-tasks&#34;&gt;Deployment Task&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guides: Defining Your Application Baseline</title>
      <link>/guides/userguide/packaging-applications/2-defining-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/guides/userguide/packaging-applications/2-defining-applications/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;using-the-_application_-list-view-for-adding-or-deleting&#34;&gt;Using the &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; List View for Adding or Deleting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; List View accessible from the left hand &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; menu option. This will take you to a list of all &lt;em&gt;Application Base Versions&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Application Versions&lt;/em&gt; to which you have access. There is a row for every &lt;em&gt;Environment&lt;/em&gt; to which the &lt;em&gt;Application Base Version&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Application Version&lt;/em&gt; has been deployed.  For this reason, there will be multiple entries for the same &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; if it has been deployed to multiple &lt;em&gt;Environments&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list view is organized on the following columns:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;List Column&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Version&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Application Base Version&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Application Version&lt;/em&gt; number.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Domain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Domain&lt;/em&gt; to which the &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; belongs.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Application Base Version&lt;/em&gt; from which the &lt;em&gt;Application Version&lt;/em&gt; was created. This will be empty for the &lt;em&gt;Application Base Version&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Environment&lt;/em&gt; to which the &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; has been deployed. Each &lt;em&gt;Environment&lt;/em&gt; will represent a different row in the List View table.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last Deployment to Environment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Deployment Log number.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Completed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The date and time of the last deployment to the listed &lt;em&gt;Environment&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Success or Fail.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also use the Filter bar, represented by a funnel icon, to reorder your &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; List View by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Domain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last Deployment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Result&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Version&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Double click on an item to see the &lt;em&gt;Dashboard&lt;/em&gt; view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;additional-tabs-from-the-_application_-list-view&#34;&gt;Additional Tabs from the &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; List View&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; List View has the following Tabs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Tab&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Refresh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Refreshes the browser.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Base&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Allows you to Add a new &lt;em&gt;Application Base Version&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Version&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Creates a copy of the selected &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; in the list, creating a new &lt;em&gt;Application Version&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delete&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deletes the selected item. However, you must delete the &lt;em&gt;Applications&lt;/em&gt; starting from the newest to the oldest.  The &lt;em&gt;Application Base Version&lt;/em&gt; would be deleted last. Sorting by &amp;ldquo;Version&amp;rdquo; gives you the order.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tasks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Displays all &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; Tasks available for the selected item based on the Tasks defined to the &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; Domain. See &lt;a href=&#34;/guides/userguide/first-steps/2-defining-domains/#tasks&#34;&gt;Tasks&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;List&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Displays the List View.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Map&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Displays a global Map of all versions of the &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;em&gt;Components&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;viewing-and-editing-with-the-_application_-dashboard&#34;&gt;Viewing and Editing with the &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; Dashboard&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dashboard view displays all information related to a specific &lt;em&gt;Application Base Version&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Application Version&lt;/em&gt;. The Dashboard view has two additional tab options - Package Components and Versions.  Below are the Details for an &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Details&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Domain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The fully qualified path of the &lt;em&gt;Domain&lt;/em&gt; that the &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; is to be associated with, showing all parent &lt;em&gt;Domains&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Name of your &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Owner Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Owned by a User or Group.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Owner&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Name of User or Group.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Description of the &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Created&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The date the &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; was added.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modified&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The date the &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; was updated.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_application_-dependencies&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; Dependencies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dependency list shows all of your &lt;em&gt;Package Components&lt;/em&gt;. This will remain empty until you assign &lt;em&gt;Components&lt;/em&gt; to your &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt;. You can manually assign &lt;em&gt;Package Components&lt;/em&gt; by using the &lt;em&gt;Package Components&lt;/em&gt; tab at the top of your &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; Dashboard. Alternatively, the recommended method is to automate the collection of this data via a &lt;a href=&#34;/guides/userguide/integrations/ci-cd_integrations/&#34;&gt;CI/CD Command Line Interface (CLI)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vulnerabilities&#34;&gt;Vulnerabilities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your &lt;em&gt;Application&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; vulnerabilities are derived by aggregating all of your &lt;em&gt;Package Component&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; vulnerabilities to the &amp;rsquo;logical&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; level. Vulnerabilities are displayed based on each &lt;em&gt;Component&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; SBOM. This data is automatically populated when one or more of your &lt;em&gt;Package Components&lt;/em&gt; have an SBOM that produced vulnerability data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note - This list may be incomplete if one or more of your &lt;em&gt;Package Components&lt;/em&gt; do not have an associated SBOM that can be used to gather vulnerability data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sbom&#34;&gt;SBOM&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your &lt;em&gt;Application&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; SBOM is derived by aggregating all of your &lt;em&gt;Package Component&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; SBOMs to the &amp;rsquo;logical&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note - This list may be incomplete if one or more of your &lt;em&gt;Package Components&lt;/em&gt; do not have an associated SBOM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;log-history&#34;&gt;Log History&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Applications&lt;/em&gt; can be deployed many times, to the same or different locations (&lt;em&gt;Environments&lt;/em&gt;). For every Deployment, the Log History will show all deployments based on &amp;ldquo;Result&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Date&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-value-configurations&#34;&gt;Key Value Configurations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Value Configurations are Value Pairs for managing associative arrays assigned to the &lt;em&gt;Object&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Value Pairs can be assigned at multiple levels, from the Global &lt;em&gt;Domain&lt;/em&gt; down to an individual &lt;em&gt;Component&lt;/em&gt; and have a &amp;ldquo;scope.&amp;rdquo; Lower level Objects can override a higher level Object.  Below is the order in which Key Value Pairs can be overridden:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Object&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Contains all Environment variables and any &amp;ldquo;additional Key Value Pairs&amp;rdquo; set by the user when running that task.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Overrides any Global Key Value Pairs during a deployment.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Overrides the &lt;em&gt;Environment&lt;/em&gt; Key Value Pairsduring a deployment.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Endpoint&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Overrides the &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; Key Value Pairs during a deployment.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Component&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Overrides the  &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; Key Value Pairs during a deployed.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Value Pairs can be given any Name and a Value. Use +Add to add Key Value Pairs to the table. Use Save to confirm.  Use the checkbox to Delete or Edit a Key Value Pair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trends&#34;&gt;Trends&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Trends graph shows the success or failure rates overtime as well at the time required for the last 10 deployments. If an &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; deployment takes longer than previous deployments, there is an issue with the deployment logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;deployed-environments&#34;&gt;Deployed Environments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you record deployments via the Ortelius CLI, you can capture deployment data showing which &lt;em&gt;Application Versions&lt;/em&gt; have been deployed an &lt;em&gt;Environment&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;last-deployment-difference-based-on-environment&#34;&gt;Last Deployment Difference Based on Environment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When tracking versions, the Difference Graph shows what changed in the last deployment between the previous deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;audit-trail&#34;&gt;Audit Trail&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Audit Trail displays audit entries for any changes or deployments that impact this object. It includes all changes in the object including &lt;em&gt;User&lt;/em&gt; date and time, and deployments with unique numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For deployment audits, select a deployment number to see the details including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Access&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Log&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The output of the deployment.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Files&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Any files or objects deployed.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step Duration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deployment Steps with time required to execute.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback Loop&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Shows what was updated starting from &lt;em&gt;Component&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also Subscribe or Comment to an Audit Entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subscribe: Allows you to receive information about the selected deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comment: Click on &amp;lsquo;Comment&amp;rsquo; to add information. There is a field above the list labeled &amp;ldquo;Say something about this Application&amp;rdquo; that can have comments placed into it, and files can be attached to the comment as well. Entering text into this field activates the Add Message button. Click to save the comment as a line in the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add Files to Comments: Click on the paperclip icon to add a file to the message.  Once done, click on the &amp;ldquo;Add Message&amp;rdquo; button. These attachments can later be retrieved by clicking on the paperclip icon which then displays the name of the file within a list. Choose the file to download it into the your default Download directory on your local computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;access&#34;&gt;Access&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Users&lt;/em&gt; within designated &lt;em&gt;Groups&lt;/em&gt; can update or view the &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt;. To add a &lt;em&gt;Group&lt;/em&gt; to one of the access lists, drag and drop the &lt;em&gt;Group&lt;/em&gt; from the Available Groups list onto desired access list. All &lt;em&gt;Users&lt;/em&gt; who belong to a &lt;em&gt;Group&lt;/em&gt; within an Access lists will be granted access to the &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Access&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;View&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Any &lt;em&gt;User&lt;/em&gt; in any &lt;em&gt;Group&lt;/em&gt; within this list can see the selected &lt;em&gt;Component&lt;/em&gt; in the List View.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Change&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Any &lt;em&gt;User&lt;/em&gt; in any &lt;em&gt;Group&lt;/em&gt; within this list can make changes to the &lt;em&gt;Component&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deploy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Any &lt;em&gt;User&lt;/em&gt; in any &lt;em&gt;Group&lt;/em&gt; within this list can deploy the &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt;.  Restrictions are based on the Access defined at the &lt;em&gt;Environment&lt;/em&gt; level.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;package-components-tab&#34;&gt;Package Components Tab&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tab contains all the &lt;em&gt;Components&lt;/em&gt; that make up an &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt;, linked together in order of deployment if needed using a blueprint designer. Click on the &lt;em&gt;Component&lt;/em&gt; Selector on the right side to see the available &lt;em&gt;Components&lt;/em&gt; based on &lt;em&gt;Domains&lt;/em&gt; and Categories. A Category acts as a tag or label assigned at the &lt;em&gt;Component&lt;/em&gt; level and are not specific to &lt;em&gt;Domains&lt;/em&gt;.  &lt;em&gt;Domains&lt;/em&gt; are identified with a sitemap icon. A Category is identified with a Tag icon. Selecting either expands the options to show all available &lt;em&gt;Components&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click and drag a &lt;em&gt;Component&lt;/em&gt; from the list on the far right side and drop it into the Assigned &lt;em&gt;Components&lt;/em&gt; area. It will appear in the area as a box containing the name of the &lt;em&gt;Component&lt;/em&gt;. It automatically links to the last &lt;em&gt;Component&lt;/em&gt;. Right click on the connecting line, select &amp;ldquo;Delete this Connection&amp;rdquo;.Create by Click on the anchor (the green dot at the bottom of the &lt;em&gt;Component&lt;/em&gt;)  to create a new connector. Then drag and drop it onto another &lt;em&gt;Component&lt;/em&gt;. This determines the order in which the &lt;em&gt;Components&lt;/em&gt; will be deployed. Each &lt;em&gt;Component&lt;/em&gt; contains &lt;em&gt;Component Items&lt;/em&gt; also linked together in the order to be executed.  For a microservice implementation, they can all be linked to the &amp;ldquo;start point&amp;rdquo;. This means they will be deployed in parallel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOTE: At least one &lt;em&gt;Component&lt;/em&gt; must be connected to the &amp;ldquo;start point&amp;rdquo; or the deployment will fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-publish-new-_application-versions_-automatically-via-continuous-delivery&#34;&gt;How to Publish New &lt;em&gt;Application Versions&lt;/em&gt; Automatically via Continuous Delivery&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Configure a continuous delivery system to automatically update new &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt; versions each time a new GitCommit triggers a new &lt;em&gt;Component&lt;/em&gt; to be consumed by your &lt;em&gt;Application&lt;/em&gt;. Ortelius in the workflow performs this continuous versioning of new &lt;em&gt;Components&lt;/em&gt; and their consuming &lt;em&gt;Applications&lt;/em&gt;.  For more information, see &lt;a href=&#34;/guides/userguide/integrations/ci-cd_integrations/&#34;&gt;Using Ortelius with CI/CD&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
